eartheasy.com 2018-10-27

# Privacy & Security | Eartheasy.com

This is our privacy policy and, if you landed here, it means that you want to learn how we process your personal data at:

**Eartheasy**  
service@eartheasy.com  
605-55 E Cordova St.  
Vancouver, BC  
V6A0A5

and how we protect your privacy. We believe ensuring the security of your personal information is an important part of our job, and we strive to protect any personal information you may provide us. Your personal information is not lent or sold to anyone for any purpose.

### Essential information we collect

In operating our store, it is essential for us to capture some information about your device, such as your IP address and information related to your visit when you browse our store. For example, this might include time-stamp, the last page or product you visited, the indication that you logged in. We do that in order to:

  * remember who you are after you log in so that you do not need to authenticate at each click; 
  * monitor if our website is running with the high performance we are dedicated to providing; 
  * let you browse between products without having to start back from the home page at each click; 
  * remember if you put something in your shopping cart before you decide to checkout; and
  * control that your data is processed securely.

We call the information mentioned above “essential information” and we collect it through the use of cookies. Cookies are small text files that most websites use. A website places cookies in the web browser and then reads the information collected through the cookies every time the user performs an action. Without enabling this mechanism and this kind of cookies (first-party cookies), we could not provide you with the smooth experience that you expect while you are navigating.

### Order information you expressly provide

If you buy something from our store, we will need more specific information about you. To fully process your order and ship the merchandise you selected, we need your personal data such as your first and last name, your email address and your shipping and billing address. We also use your contact and order information to send you communication related to the processing of your order. We will ask you to provide this information in our “checkout page” before letting you finalize your purchase with the payment.

### Accounts

You can sign up for an account if you’d like. This will make us happy because it confirms your interest in our store. It should also make you happy because we will remember your information and, when you decide to buy our products, you do not have to provide all of your information over again -- you just have to log-in. We also give you the possibility to easily withdraw your consent and delete your account. Just connect with us at [service@eartheasy.com](mailto:service@eartheasy.com).

### Partial Purchases

If you have started to buy one of our products, but have not completed the purchase, you may have provided partial information, such as your email. In that case, we might send you an email to remind you about your interest. If you are not comfortable in receiving further emails of this kind, we will give you a simple opportunity to opt-out, by clicking the unsubscribe button on any email you receive. Your privacy means a lot to us and we will stop sending you these communications right away.

### Personalization

We also use some specific information related to your visit, such as the timestamp of your visit, the page or the product you viewed, where you are coming from (if you came to our store because you clicked on an advertisement or you just opened our direct link). This is very similar to the “essential information,” but we use it to provide you with a personalized experience. The information on your visit provides us with insights on your interests and allows us to send you relevant communications. We capture this information through cookies, called a "beacon," that we allow you to block.

### Newsletter Subscription

Newsletters are sent only to users who choose to provide us with their email address. Our newsletter subscriber database is never sold, rented or loaned to any other parties.

We collect aggregate information regarding open rates, page views, and generated sales from our HTML email newsletters. Aggregate information does not personally identify individuals.

### Opting Out

If you wish to have any of your personal information removed from our database, or if you no longer want us to send any further communications to you, please send an e-mail to [service@eartheasy.com](mailto:service@eartheasy.com). If you simply want to stop receiving emails from us, simply click the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us.

### Links

This web site contains links to other sites and advertisements. This privacy statement only applies to information collected by our web site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices and policies of these third parties.

### How do we process your information?

We use an external provider to run our store, BigCommerce. [BigCommerce](https://www.bigcommerce.com/) is based in the US and is a participant in the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and committed to providing best-in-class service and data protection. You can check its participation in the Privacy Shield [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TN78AAG&status=Active) on the official site of The International Trade Administration (ITA), U.S. Department of Commerce.

Through BigCommerce, we also use other, highly specialized external providers to provide the most competitive services.

### Other Service providers

**Payment** : ​Our store is PCI-DSS compliant (a very strict industry standard with requirements for the security of credit card information), however  we want use Paypal to process your credit card information.

**Shipping** : ​We integrate with a number of shipping companies such as FedEx and USPS to fulfill your orders. 

Partnering with highly specialized external companies allows us to focus on what we do best: selling great products.

### How can you control your personal data?

If any any time, you wish to have your personal information removed from our store and customer records, simply email: [service@eartheasy.com](mailto:service@eartheasy.com) and we will remove your information and confirm that we have done so in an email to you.

### How long do we keep your data?

We keep your data for as long as you have an account with us. We also keep some data for security investigation. Most importantly, we have specific obligations for fraud detection and tax reasons. Therefore, we might need to retain certain data even if you ask to delete it. 

### Do we have any legal obligations when handling your data?

Many. We might need to share your personal information to comply with applicable legal obligations. For example, you might need to keep records for tax reasons or fraud detection.

### Who can you reach out to for privacy matters?

You can contact our Data Privacy Leader, by emailing service@eartheasy.com

### Any update?

If we update our Privacy Policy to reflect a change or improvement of our services or a new legal obligation, we will publish the new version on our website, and we will make it clear on our home page so it will be visible as you enter our store.
